Welcome back.
Have you ever considered that your primary role
isn't just to manage work, but it's to multiply talent?
We call this the manager multiplier effect.
The idea is very simple.
Your leadership is a catalyst.
Your actions, your coaching, your alignment,
don't just add to your team's output, they multiply it.
When you effectively coach one player,
their increased performance and engagement and alignment
lifts the entire team and drives measurable business results.
You're not on the sidelines.
You're driving how your direct report
and your broader team applies M.V.P. in real time.
I saw this with a manager named David.
He invested the time in coaching his player, Kim,
on her presentation skills.
Now, Kim then led a high stakes client pitch
that her team won.
The winning boosted the team morale,
secured a major contract,
and got the whole team recognized by senior leadership.
David's one coaching investment was multiplied
into a team win and a business win.
Your play is to identify one area
where your player's growth could have a multiplier effect
on the team.
Is it their technical skills?
Maybe their ability to collaborate?
Note this in your playbook.
This becomes a strategic focus for your coaching.
Think about your team's biggest goal for this quarter.
How could you align stakeholders outside of your immediate team
to align on shared goals and execution?
Have you translated direction from your senior leaders
into clear, actionable steps for your team?
How can your player's development in this program
directly contribute to achieving that goal?
Could this insight to your direct report
create greater alignment through the 90-day plan?
Let's be specific.
Use the multiplier effect.
Drill in your playbook to capture your thoughts
on these questions.
In our next segment, we'll get tactical
about how to set the stage for this kind of impact
with your player.